♪
[LAFALLE] Is this all
of the silver sugar?
Huh-huh.
I see. Kill him.
- I refuse.
- [gasps]
Very well.
[MALE CAPTIVE 23A]
No! Please don't!
[screams]
Let's return.
Huh?
[gasps]
I thought that I was clear.
I wanted you to craft
a set of fief pieces
like the Viscount made.
This is distorted garbage.
Uh.
Perhaps I should get
someone different, after all.
[gasps]
If you let me try it again.
I can!
Clean this up.
Ah.
[sighs]
- [LUSUL] Anne?
- Huh?
- Oh.
- [giggles]
I have returned!
Hello, there.
So tell me,
why are all the other fairies
content with living
in a place like this?
[LUSUL]
They don't talk about it often
but when they do, they say that
it's better than
being controlled by humans.
[ANNE]
I see.
There are over
fifty of us here now,
so it's harder to find
our meals.
Oh, did Challe
tell you anything?
Is Master Lafalle planning
to make a big move soon?
[ANNE]
I don't know.
Aw, that's all right.
What's this? Silver sugar?
What's that doing in here?
[ANNE]
Lafalle wants something.
- [gasps]
- I didn't tell you this yet
but I'm actually
a silver sugar artisan.
Lafalle wants me to make him
some sugar confections.
[LUSUL]
Sugar confection?
I've heard that
those are very sweet.
You've never eaten any?
Then I'll make some for you
right now.
- Oh, would you?
- Sure.
♪
[LUSUL]
Amazing!
They look just
like the herb berries
that I was born from!
Did you use some magic spell?
No, there's no magic to it.
Go on, give it a try.
Are you sure?
Mm-hmm.
[smiles]
[inhales]
[exhales]
It's wonderful.
Not only that,
but it feels like
I'm bursting with energy now!
[smiles]
I'm glad.
Say, Anne?
Would you mind
if I shared this
with the others?
I think it might help
all the injured fairies
- feel better!
- Injured?
Hmm. Every time
they return from the outside,
they're all covered in wounds.
It looks like it's painful.
Oh. Yes!
Please take it to them.
And if there's not enough,
I'll make more.
Thank you so much!
[pants]
[smiles]
Hmm?
That fairy came
to talk to you again?
Listen, Challe.
- [CHALLE] Hmm?
- Mm. Nothing.
♪
[ANNE] No. I can't ask him
what he's being forced to do.
And even if he told me,
I'm not able to help.
[LAFALLE]
In order to be happy,
humans and fairies should stay
with their own kind.
If you truly want
what's best for Challe,
the answer is clear.
[ANNE]
Challe,
have you ever met another
precious stone fairy?
A female precious stone fairy?
Why are you asking?
[ANNE]
No reason.
I was just wondering
if there was anyone
you might fall in love with.
Speak plainly.
It's just when you told me
that you would stay
with me forever,
I was really happy.
But then,
I don't know if it's fair of me
to rely on those words.
I want you to be happy
and not sacrifice everything
for me.
- So, Challe, if you ever--
- Anne.
Huh?
[CHALLE]
Rely on me.
- Uh...
- Please.
[LAFALLE] You will cause him
nothing but sorrow.
[gasps]
♪
- Are you all right?
- [MALE FAIRY] I think so.
[MALE RAIRY 1]
Somebody help me.
- [ANNE] Lusul?
- Huh?
[LASUL]
Anne! Huh?
[LASUL] Are those?
[ANNE] Yes, I made a few more.
[ANNE]
I hope they'll be useful.
How generous!
We've got a lot of injuries
to treat today.
Look what Anne brought!
Could you give them
to the fairies in the back?
- Hope you enjoy.
- [groans]
Helpful.
[ANNE]
Um...
- Ha.
- Don't worry,
he's more grateful than
he'll ever say.
I think he just hates the idea
of thanking a human,
that's all.
[LASUL] I've never had to
serve anyone myself,
but they all seem extremely
resentful of humankind.
I see. Hmm.
[MITHRIL] Look. Thanking you
and repaying you
are two very different things!
Is something wrong?
No, I'm perfectly fine.
It's just,
I want to go home soon.
There are things
I should be doing.
How do you all feel?
As long as someone else
is holding your wings,
you can't do as you please
and you can never go
where you want to go.
Do as we please?
Don't you want something?
[sighs]
I can't think of anything.
But do either of you
have things you want?
- Hmm.
Well,
I would like to see the ocean.
I've never been there,
even once.
Ocean? What is this "ocean?"
You don't know?
The ocean is vaster
than any kingdom is.
It's basically a gigantic,
salty puddle.
We can't go there!
We would all drown!
[laughter]
[chuckles]
I wish I could think of a way
to take all of your wings
back for you.
If I could, then you would
finally get to be free.
I'm confused.
None of our wings are
in human hands anymore, right?
The way I see it, we are free.
[ANNE]
You've just changed masters.
From the humans to your King,
Lafalle.
It's not right.
[ALL]
Huh?
[smiles]
- [JONAS] Oh, there you are.
- Hmm?
[JONAS] Mr. Hingley wants to
assemble the pieces now.
All right, I'll start heading
that way, then.
[JONAS]
Good.
[KEITH]
Jonas.
Hmm?
Do you think Anne
is really going to come back?
Of course, she will.
But twenty days
have already gone by
and we still don't have a clue
where to find her
and the weather's turning cold.
[slimes] I know, but...
Anne won't give up.
[JONAS] She's headstrong
to the point
of being a stubborn idiot.
And that's how I know
she'll be just fine.
I suppose that makes sense.
So, do you plan
to keep on working
at Paige after all this?
Past
the Holy Beginnings Festival?
Actually.
I'll go back
to Radcliffe Workshop.
[KEITH]
I'm surprised.
You and I will both be there,
Kieth!
I know my skills
don't compare to yours
but still I think it'll be good
for me to try a bit harder.
Just this once. I want to be...
To be as headstrong
as Anne is, right?
That's not it!
That'd be absurd.
It's just a thought
I've been having.
I see.
Now, hurry up
and come back inside
before we both get scolded.
Right.
I can see they did
the same thing here.
It was prudent
to increase our troops,
but with no leads,
our hands are tied.
I can't believe
they were careful enough
to leave no trace.
[sighs] If we don't put
a stop to this now
there will be more.
Yes definitely.
Oh.
It can't be.
What is it?
Well, my lord.
I think I just found the lead
we're looking for.
Are you sure?
I'm allowed to be free at last?
Listen, could you give
a message to the girl, please?
Pardon me?
The human girl
who's usually with you.
Would you ask her
to make sugar confections
for us again today,
if she's that's all right?
[groans]
Ah, I see.
[CHALLE] I wondered
why she was making those.
[MALE FAIRY 22A] If she's able,
give them to Lusul.
[smiles]
- Oh.
- [CHALLE] I'll tell her.
[grunts and groans]
You lot can go ahead
and take them back now.
Challe and I have business
to attend to.
As of today, we're done
gathering our allies.
[LAFALLE]
Tomorrow, we attack that town.
We've increased our numbers
beyond what the fortress
can support
in order to keep
our soldiers cared for,
we'll need more humans
at our disposal.
You'll attack for that?
[LAFALLE]
This will be our territory.
Starting from these lands
we will reclaim our kingdom.
Once we do,
the freedom of all our fellow
fairies will be restored.
[CHALLE] Is he telling me
his honest feelings?
No.
I see. He's also...
You seem happy.
Is that how it looks?
Do you find revenge fun?
Uh?
So, what happened
to your other wing?
You appeared suddenly,
claimed that you were
fated to be the fairy King,
and started gathering allies.
No one knows
you from before that.
You said you were born
before I was.
Why did you wait
a hundred years
to set your plan in motion?
Perhaps you were unable?
There's only one reason
why that would be.
Stop talking.
[CHALLE] You were under
the control of humans.
[LAFALLE]
You will be silent, Challe!
Unlike me, you were aware
that you had been chosen
to assume the destiny
of the next fairy King,
so to be captured
and controlled by humankind
must've been particularly
maddening for you.
And once you had finally broken
free from their clutches.
I said, that's enough talking!
Don't tell me you've forgotten
that I'm still in possession
of your wing, Challe.
I know.
Let me guess, you hold on to
all those fairies wings,
because you can't learn
to trust.
Is that the reason
you force anyone
with two wings
to surrender one?
Because you're angry
that one is all you have left?
[breathes]
From where I'm standing,
it looks like you hate humans
and other fairies.
But why is that?
Because fairies
betrayed you once.
That's how you were captured.
How dare you insult me!
[CHALLE] This whole endeavor
is a plot for revenge.
You attack the humans
out of rage and resentment
and you're forcing your allies
to yield to you.
[LAFALLE]
Is that the end of your speech?
In order to regain freedom
for all fairies
we have no choice but to
hate and attack humankind.
The allies I'm organizing
are those
whose lives have no purpose.
Controlling them keeps them
from doing stupid things.
And furthermore,
if I do experience
a bit of enjoyment
from revenge and control
well, where's the harm in that?
If you want to be a King
revenge and control
should not be
among the things you enjoy.
[grunts]
I made more today.
If you need them.
Sugar confections!
That's very helpful, thank you!
[ANNE]
It was my pleasure.
- [MALE FAIRY 23A] Why?
- Huh?
What do you stand to gain here?
Why would a human go
and make confections
for fairies?
Because I heard that you might
need them to help with your--
[LAFALLE] What are you doing?
[ANNE] Uh!
- Oh.
- Well, Silver Sugar Master?
Explain yourself.
[LAFALLE] What you made for me
was little more than garbage,
yet for the other fairies,
you create these beautiful
works of art?
I'm sorry I'll make some
for you as well!
But this batch
is meant for them
so please let them keep it!
It appears
that you didn't understand
the meaning of my question.
Why did you make these
exquisite confections for them
and present me
with such worthless trash?
I don't know.
For some reason,
yours didn't come out as well.
I just...
[chuckles]
Then you can't make
sugar confections for me?
Because you reject me
from the bottom of your heart?
It's not that!
You truly are
a troublesome girl!
- Ah...
- Come!
Oh. Wait, Master!
Please don't go!
Why not?
Um, it's just that,
I'd like to know
what exactly you're planning
to do with her.
There's no reason to keep
a pet human who has no use.
But, Master Lafalle
she is being useful, sir.
She treated all our wounds.
If she can't make
sugar confections for me,
then I don't want
to keep her here.
I can easily capture
another Silver Sugar Master
who's better suited
to our needs.
[grunts and groans]
[whimpering]
[LAFALLE]
I'd given up long ago.
I accepted
that there wasn't a fairy
who could live at my side.
No one was ever born
from the diamond,
and I wasn't sure that
the obsidian was alive.
Any other fairy
was out of the question.
They're ignorant,
thoughtless fools.
If I hadn't taken
control of them,
who knows what sorts of messes
they would have made.
Then at last, the obsidian
fairy Challe Fen Challe,
appeared before my eyes.
Yet, to my outrage,
he had aligned himself
with a human girl
and was supporting humankind
as a whole.
If you didn't exist,
I have to imagine
he would think differently.
He'd be at my side, I know it.
But you ruined him.
Hmm. That's not true!
Challe would still be the way
he is, with or without me!
If you want to be with him,
I think you should return
everyone's wings!
You need to see people
the same way Challe does,
- and then he may want--
- You do not speak
his name that way, human scum!
Challe and I have
the same purpose.
We were both born
to become the fairy King.
The two of us were handpicked
by destiny.
The fairy King?
- [CHALLE] What has happened?
- [both] Huh?
[LUSUL]
Oh, Challe.
- It's Anne!
- [gasps]
Don't say that Lusul!
Master Lafalle
will kill you for it!
- [gasps]
- Are you content with him
keeping you all just like pets?
Living in fear of him?
Catering to all his whims?
How is that any different than
serving a human master?
- [grunts]
- Aw.
I will protect
all that matters to me
and I will not be
Lafalle's pet.
[CHALLE]
What has Anne done to you?
If you hate her because
she's human, then say no more.
Otherwise,
tell me where she is!
What has happened to Anne?
[MALE FAIRY 22A] She was
taken by Master Lafalle.
[ANNE] Challe is supposed to
become the fairy King?
[gasps]
- Ah.
- I'll just lie to Challe,
tell him that I released you.
Some time will go by
then he'll forget
that you ever existed at all.
I'll chip away at him slowly.
If it takes a hundred years,
I know I'll change
his way of thinking.
But first, I will need to
get you out of the way.
Uh.
[gasps]
I warned you, Lafalle.
If you threatened Anne,
I'd cut you down!
The others told you
what I was up to, did they?
They really are
such spineless idiots.
It's a good thing
I've taken all of their wings
otherwise they would be
just impossible to organize.
You couldn't even get
a handful of fairies
to obey you willingly.
Some King you would be.
[laughs]
That's laughable,
are you suggesting that if it
were you pulling the strings,
you could wrangle
that many fairies
without taking
their wings away?
[CHALLE]
A true King has no need
of his fairies' freedom.
Me? I would seek
another way to lead.
You're so naive.
The humans would strip us
of our pride
before you had the chance.
[chuckles]
It seems I am
the only fairy King after all,
which means,
I must subdue you as well.
[gasps]
[Challe gasps]
- [gasps]
- [groans]
- Oh, no.
- Anne, run!
- But, Challe!
Just go, you're in the way!
Oh. Huh.
Mm-hmm.
Ah.